

Rubén Vázquez

33 years Querétaro, México 558415 0000 <u>ruben@miweb.mx</u> https://ruvaz.github.io

I am a passionate professional in my work, Computer Systems Engineer, Linux Server Administrator, Full-Stack Programmer. I am characterized by high attention to detail, I am self-critical, proactive and responsible. I have experience in the area of Web Development, and in Linux Server Administration.

EDUCATION

2010

UNIVERSIDAD DEL VALLE DE MÉXICO

Computer Systems engineer University degree and professional certificate

2004

Center of Technological and Service Studies

Computer Technician

WORK EXPERIENCE

 APRIL 2017 – AUGUST 2017 MEDTRAINER

Digital Developer Sr

Development of web applications for administration of hospitals, clinics, or companies in the health sector of the United States. Control and administration of services, documents, contracts, policies, insurance, incident control, employee privileges under the rules established by the American law, online courses, notifications and document status. *Implement with framework Synfony*, *php, mysql, Azure, javascript, Scrum, json, ajax, bootstrap, jquery, gitLab, Jira, Confluence, SourceTree, Linux Shell.*

JULY 2012 – FEBRUARY 2017
 MACMILLAN – EDICIONES CASTILLO

Digital Developer Sr

Administration of Linux Servers, User control, user control and administration of user and groups privileges. Programming of automated scripts, configuration of web domains in the servers, configuration of automatic backups, management of server resources, implementation of virtual servers for testing, company web infrastructure manager, database administrator and content management. Development of different applications to meet the needs of the company. Programming of educational platforms, online language exams, administration of students and candidates for certifications in English level knowledge. Administration of social media, mailing, Google Analytics, Adwords, Adsense and ARCO rights manager of the company. Using *Php, Javascript, Laravel, VueJs, AngularJS, Jquery, Json, Bootstrap, CSS, Centos, Shell, SSH, MySQL, VPS, VmWare, Virtual box, Webservice, Github, Bitbucket, PhpStorm, WebStorm*

FEBRUARY 2012 – MAY 2012
 QBE INSURANCE GROUP

Informix 4GL Genero Developer

Development of internal applications for the area of collections and reinsurance, creation of reports for various information requirements, support in closing monthly balances. Using *IBM Informix 4GL*, *Genero Studio 4js*, *UNIX HP*, *Shell*, *TurtoiseSVN*.

FEBRUARY 2011 – JANUARY 2012
 GRUPO TELEVISA

Development of Technologies for television production

Provision of the technology services required for different productions in national and international television. Implementation and programming of various technologies used in the production teams of the company. Adaptation of graphics systems and their communication to data coming from web portals for interaction with the public during live transmission. Using *Perl*, *Php*, *Java*, *Mysql*, *Webservice*, *Linux*, *Json*, *Trakcab*, *Virtual 3d*, *3DMax*.

AUGUST 2010 – JANUARY 2011 SAGARPA

Software engineer

Service of adaptation of the Budget, Accounting and Finance System (SIPREC) to new regulations requested by the SHCP, in matters of Budgetary Policy and Government Accounting for electronic billing. Using *Visual Basic*, *Sql Server*, *Stores procedures*, *Informix*, *Crystal Reports*, *ASP 2.0*, *XML*.

MAY 2008 – JULY 2010 RED RADIAN SAPI DE CV

Infrastructure Administrator

Administration and configuration of Linux servers for use as IVR hybrids to provide VoIP telephony. Use of virtual servers for testing. Administration and programming of the administrative platform for customer control, balances, recharges and assignment of telephone lines. Programming Softphones, Extensions, Switch, Voicemail, Conferencing, Automatic Call Distribution SIP protocols, IAX. Management of infrastructure services of information systems (mail server, application server based on Windows and Linux platforms). Using Windows Server, Linux VPS, Vmware, Debian, Asterisk, Php, Mysql, Bootstrap, Css, Iquery, Shell, SSH.

JUN 2017 – MAY 2008 SEPROCESA SA DE CV

Programmer analyst

Database Management for Microsoft CRM Great Plans in SQL Server 2005, Windows server management, Active Director handling, user control, permission assignment. Creation of reports and programming solutions for internal processes for inventory control and equipment management. Personnel training for the use of CRM, network monitoring and administration of the Analog Hybrid Telephony / VoIP system. Monthly information loads and reports for company closures. Using *Windows Server, CRM Microsoft Great Plans, SQL Server, Cristal Reports, Microsoft Access, Visual Studio.*

PROGRAMIN LANGUAGE

INFORMIX 4GL	50%
ARQUITECTURA JAVA	40%
PHP	90%
JAVASCRIPT	50%
PERL	50%
C#	40%
VISUAL BASIC	40%

FRAMEWORKS

SYNFONY LARAVEL COMPOSER JQUERY VUEJS ANGULARJS BOOTSTRAP IONIC	85% 85% 80% 80% 70% 50% 90%
.NET	50%

DESIGN TOOLS

ADOBE PHOTOSHOP	80%
ADOBE ILUSTRATOR	60%
ACORN	80%
ADOBE FIREWORKS	90%

DEVELOPMENT ENVIRONMENTS

PHPSTORM	85%
WEBSTORM	70%
SUBLIME TEXT	90%
BRACKETS	90%
ECLIPSE - APTANA	90%
NETBEANS	50%
VISUAL STUDIO	60%

OTHER KNOWLEDGE

AUTOMATED SCRIPTS	80%
ADMINISTRATION OF USERS, GROUPS AND PERMITS	90%
(LINUX)	
ADAPTABLE WEB DESIGN	90%
OPTIMIZATION FOR SEARCH ENGINES (SEO)	70%
WEB DESIGN ON WORDPRESS, JOOMLA, DRUPAL,	90%
MOODLE,	
WEB PERFORMANCE	70%
ADMINISTRATION OF LINUX SERVERS (CENTERS,	80%
REDHAT, DEBIAN)	

COURSES

JAVASCRIPT: UNDERSTANDING THE WEIRD PARTS

12 / 2016 Udemy.com

LEARN AND UNDERSTAND ANGULARJS

08/2016 Udemy.com

• ANGULAR 1.5 Y 2

06/2016 Lynda.com

LARAVEL 5

08/2015 Laracast.com

GENERO STUDIO 4JS, INFORMIX 4GL

02/2012

ASTERISK IVR BASIC, AND INTERMEDIATE 24/11/2009 - 28/11/2009

• LINUX INTERMEDIATE COURSE

24/11/2009 - 28/11/2009

LANGUAGE

ENGLISH

Written: Basic 30%

Speaking: Intermediate: 40%

Reading: Intermediate: 70%